# SUBHAJIT PAL

# Front-End Developer | ReactJs

+91-8013415264 @ subhajit0408@gmail.com @ linkedin.com/in/subhajit-pal-25260266/ @ https://github.com/palsubha04

Kolkata, India

#### **SUMMARY**

Energetic Senior Front-End Developer with over 7+ years of professional experience and 4+ years of experience in FrontEnd Development focusing on React-based applications. Proficient with JavaScript, TypeScript, and Git. Hands-on experience in identifying web-based user interactions along with designing & implementing highly-responsive user interface components by deploying React concepts. Looking forward to adding value through my passion and expertise.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Senior Front-End Developer

#### Tech Mahindra

苗 05/2022 - Present Kolkata, India.

Contributed to frontend development with a primary focus on React-based applications.

- Developed 4+ user-focused, modern React applications resulting in 15% improved user experience.
- Identified web-based user interactions and developed highly-responsive user interface components via React concepts.
- Translated designs & wireframes into high-quality code and wrote application interface code via JavaScript following React.js workflow.
- Developed the latest user-facing features using React.js and built reusable components & front-end libraries for future use Optimized components for maximum performance across a vast array of web-capable devices and browser.

# Senior Software Developer

**=** 04/2017 - 05/2022 ♥ Kolkata, India.

Developed high quality interface components and ensured its robustness in collaboration with other team members.

- Implemented React Hooks in 5 projects, enhancing code reusability and
- Increased application performance by 40% by optimizing the web components.
- Developed and implemented responsive user interface component by using React
- Experience in working with State Management Library Redux.
- Created modular, responsive templates using modern CSS techniques and Material UI.
- Utilized Git for version control across all projects, ensuring seamless team collaboration.
- Identified and fixed issues in web properties, improving website usability.

## **EDUCATION**

# B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering

Academy of Technology

**=** 2011 - 2015

O Kolkata, India

#### **LANGUAGES**

English Proficient •••• Bengali Native ••••

Hindi Proficient ••••

#### **STRENGTHS**



## Adaptability

Quickly adapted to the sophisticated React ecosystem at IBM, contributing to major projects within the first few months.



# Collaborative

Successfully collaborated with a team of developers and content creators at Tech Mahindra, improving application performance



#### **Dedicated Learner**

Consistently kept up-to-date with the latest technologies, including a proficient understanding of React and Redux Toolkit

#### **SKILLS**

React	Rea	React Hooks		JavaScript	
TypeScript		Redux-Toolkit		Bootstrap	
Git	HTML	CSS	NodeJs		

# **CERTIFICATION**

## Advanced React and Redux

Certificate Course by Udemy focusing on advanced concepts of React and Redux.

## Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

Completed Azure Fundamental (AZ-900) Certification From Microsoft

## **PASSIONS**



#### Web Development

I love creating interactive, efficient, and userfriendly web applications that add value to businesses.



# Learning Coding Languages

Spending time deep-diving into new coding languages and web technologies stimulates and inspires me.